Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit
and today I am presenting to you the
term plan of ICC Prudential Life Insurance, which is named Hi Protest
Smart. What are the main features of this plan,
what kind of riders are there in it, can this
policy be taken by the employer,
can this policy be taken in the policy, can
you purchase this policy under a partnership firm, can you
purchase an individual policy,
what will be the income proof, how much income should be required,
what will be the education proof, and
what is the unit benefit in it, in
comparison to other companies, in what way is it
better, I have
explained all this in detail in this video, watch this video completely,
if you like my video then do like,
share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajbhar Triple FS. Now let's talk about the
10 main features of this policy. I will
tell you about the claim settlement details in detail. From 2009 till
now, the claim statement received is
not for two years but for a very long period of about 15
years.  We will
talk about Illness Benefit and Disability Rider. This is a Whole Life Insurance
policy which runs for 100 years. We will
talk about it in the section about Accidental Benefit. You get double the Life Stage
Benefit. Like if you want to make an insurance policy at the time of your child's birth or
marriage, then we will
talk about that benefit.
Flexible Pay Out Option. If
you want to take a lump sum amount or
every month in case of death, then we will talk about
how you can take the death benefit.
You have to pay the premium. In this, it is
limited or regular. We will
talk about that in details. In this,
there is a guaranteed premium relief. It does
not increase. Like in health insurance, the
premium is paid from time to time, but in this there is a
guaranteed relief. We will talk about its features. It is the
market leader and there is no survival period.
What happens in many insurance policies is that if
something like this happens, then it is said that you have to
survive for one month, or 3 months, or
6 months, only then  You will
get benefits but there will be nothing like this here, so
all these features are the main ones
of this policy and we will understand them in open detail.
Now let us see the claim settlement ratio in
a report of IRD
between 2010 to 2019, where the claim
settlement ratio has been talked about,
if you
see the claim settlement ratio of ICC Prudential for this 10 years, then it is
95.48%, for example,
in 2009-10 also the claim settlement ratio of the company was
19.17%, as of today the
highest claim settlement insurer is
99.34, but in 2009-10, Max Life's was
only 65%,
then 894, in this way their claim statement has been
and till now,
in whatever amount, they remain at number one, you
can see HDFC at number two,
you can see SBI at 83%, Bajaj at 83% in 2009  Max had 88% discount,
Tata has 65% discount,
so when you look at the clean set, then
also check the claim history and see for how long
this company is settling claims well,
this is the claim settlement rate,
if I talk about the current period, 2014,
now I will tell you about the rest of the normal features a little later,
which are most of the term plans
before that because most of your customers had
retired, premium premium premium,
more insurance,
more insurance, cheaper, cheaper butter, so this
time I am comparing you, if
not a good customer, if you are taking a term plan, that is, you are
talking about higher insurance tax, then
if you are taking insurance of 2 crores or
more or you
smoke, then this plan will be very good for you, let us
see, let us understand it with the premium, but for example, there is
a person who has taken insurance here for 30, 35, 40 and 45 years,
I have taken
insurance of 2.5 crores, I have taken this
quotation on 17th September 2023, here is the
policy, so
till 70  If it is 50 years old
then the policy term will be 35 years
and here I have kept the option of 10 years premium payment
that if you pay premium for 10 years, the
policy runs for 40 years and there is an insurance tax of 2.5 crores, then
what will be the premium of ICC,
what will be the premium of HDFC, what will be the
premium of Tata Life, what will be the premium of Max, what will be the premium of
Bajaj, what will be the premium of Kotak Life,
what will be the
premium of Birla Sun Life, what will be the premium of SBI Life Insurance, what will be the premium
of Link, the pay is
not applied here because there is no pay option of 10 pay there, so
in ICC Prudential,
if a 30 year old person pays 10 years premium and takes a
40 year policy term of 2.5 crores, then the
premium comes to 65890, now check it
in all other companies, no one is
giving you this money for 890,
secondly, at the age of 35,
you are getting an insurance tax of 2.5 crores for Rs 94254,
now try
taking 94 from any other company, you will get an insurance tax of 2.5 crores for Rs 94000, some company will pay
94000  HDFC is not giving insurance of ₹2.5 crore, it is
taking premium of ₹1 crore, Kotak is taking premium of ₹122000,
SBI is taking premium of ₹2 lakh,
ICC is taking premium of only ₹94000, for a
40 year old,
ICC is taking premium of ₹1 lakh 48000,
HDFC is taking premium of ₹176000,
Tata is taking ₹14000, Max
Life is taking ₹1.5 lakh, Bajaj is
taking one paisa, Quota is taking premium of ₹171,
SBI is taking premium of ₹2 lakh 17 thousand, for a
45 year old, you will get it for
₹185000, you will have to
pay premium for 80 years till the age of 80,
HDFC is giving it to you for ₹241,
Bajaj is giving it to you for ₹230, for Kotak, the
dialogue is getting around, if Billa is also taking you
close, then
you can see and compare it.
Which company's
product will be best for you, I am talking about September 2023.
I have
compared the smoke rate with HDFC, a top company for a minute. I do
not compare all other companies again and again, it takes a lot of time, friend. So
if I look at the smoker rate of ICC,
if someone does gambling, kesari, mawa, gutkha,
tobacco, is consuming nicotine in any way, then
after 30 years,
he will get an insurance tax of 1 crore for 28953, for
40 years. Here I have
kept a term of 40 years, the premium payment is less,
regular, I have compared both, then
ICC will give it for 28000, then
HDFC will have to pay premium every year for 33000,
at the age of 35, ICC will
give it for 40000, HDFC will give it for 47000, after 40 years,
ICC is
taking 60000, ICC is taking it for 2 lakh 28 thousand,
so you can see that the smoke rate
Which company will be more suitable for you even at the rate?
Talking about the
basic face of the policy, you
can purchase the policy in a single frame as well. In a single frame,
you will get a policy term of 20 years. The
option of regular premium and limited premium is also available. There is entry in
which you can take a policy from 18 years to 65 years. The
policy of 100 years also
runs till your second 99 years. You
can also take that online. In this, you can make premium payment
on annual, half yearly, quarterly and monthly mode. You can also purchase a rider, if it is
accidental, you can purchase a
limited premium payment term in
which you can pay premium for 5 years and
pay premium for 6 years. You can
select premium payment for 10 years, that is, you
can make payment till you are 60 years old. This is a limited pack option, that is,
if you want to run a 5-year policy for 50 years, then
also you can run it.
You have to run the policy for 50 years by paying premium for 10 years.
Suppose there is a person whose  If the
age of 35 is more, he wants to pay premium for five years
and the coverage in the policy goes up to 85, then he
can take a policy term of 50 years. This means that there is a feature of terminal illness and
disability. A
very good feature of this policy is that you get
terminal illness in it. If you see, then
all the companies of the world give you
insurance tax back benefit, but
here even if terminal illness is diagnosed,
you will be given the full insurance tax
benefit immediately. Terminal illness means
any such disease in which the doctor writes
that the death of this customer will occur
due to this disease within 6 months, then
if you take it during your lifetime,
you will get an insurance of Rs 1 crore, you
can get good treatment.
Secondly, there is a good feature in it, disability insurance. For example, if an
accident happens
and the customer becomes permanently disabled, then on
this date your premium payment is waived.
This is an in-built feature,
for this you do not have to pay a separate premium.  For
Bridal people, you will have to pay a separate premium,
whereas in this, the
disability benefit with premium way comes in its build,
you will not have to pay a separate premium, all the
options like Live Plus
etc. will come inbuilt in all the options,
in this policy you also get 34 critical illness
benefit, you can purchase it as a rider
or as a separate option,
in 34, if you have kidney failure, you went into coma, had a
heart attack, it got cancelled,
brain surgery happened, paralysis happened,
stroke happened, as soon as
you are diagnosed with any of the 34 critical illnesses given above,
you have insurance of 10 lakhs, for critical, the
entire 10 lakhs is given to you at once, it has
nothing to do with how much your medical expenses were, how much the hospital bill was, the lump sum of your insurance tax is
given to you at once,
secondly, your premium in this is a
guaranteed relief, it does not increase if
you take a critical illness policy in health insurance
or  Even if you take normal health insurance, the
insurance premium increases from time to time after a gap of five years,
but here, once you have
taken it, the premium which was paid at that time will remain the same even after the
policy term and will not increase. The
good thing about the benefit in this policy is
that there is no survival period clause here.
What happens is that in case of any such diagnosis, the
customer gets the insurance benefit only if he survives for 30 days,
but here there is nothing like that. There is zero
survival period, which means as soon as the diagnosis is done,
you will get the benefit.
Suppose someone gets a heart attack, now even if he does
not survive the heart attack or
dies, you will still get this benefit. There is
no survival period clause in this,
which is a good piece. Uncle,
in the accident benefit, you get double the amount that you purchase, that is, if
you have
taken an accident rider tax of ₹1 crore and an
accident happens, then you will get
double the amount i.e. 2 crore.  You will get it. Let us
understand it with an example. There is a 35 year old person who has
taken a normal policy of ₹1 crore and has taken a policy of ₹1 crore due to an accident. If he dies
in an accident, then the
accidental policy will double, he will get Rs. 2 crore or
3 crore.
[Music]
Whichever of the features you take, you will definitely get these.
Now in the Live Plus option,
you get an additional
rider of accidental death benefit, you can take that.
If you talk about Life in Health, you will
not get the accidental one there, but there is
criticality, which you can take from 34 of them,
and you will get the remaining three which are common.
Here, to understand all the four options, I have
taken this example of premium from the browser. This premium may be old or
new and may be different, but here, just
from the point of view of understanding, I am telling you
that there is a person whose age is 30, 35, 40, 45
or 50, he selects a policy term of 20 years and is
taking a normal policy of ₹1 crore.  If he meets with an accident worth crores tomorrow and is
taking a critical insurance benefit of Rs. 1 crore or Rs. 25 lakhs, then
what will be his premiums
in life insurance because the entire insurance is
taxed, so for example, for 30 years
onwards, it will cost Rs. 9512. What happens in life plus,
along with normal insurance, you
also get accidental tax, so you will get
Rs. 15512. What happens in life and health is
that you get normal insurance tax, you
don't get accidental tax but you get critical
insurance, so here the
insurance tax of Rs. 1 crore plus
Rs. 81 and what will be in these one, if
critical insurance of Rs. 25 lakhs, then the premium will be Rs. 20588, regular every year for 20 years, so in this way you can see the tax options, which one do you want to select as per your need, okay, but what happens in normal insurance company, you
also get back benefit,
but here you will also get debt benefit,
terminal illness and also the amount of
premium, if  If there is a permanent
disability, that means the next
premium payment is waived and there is
relief in continuing the insurance, then
you are getting three in one option,
under a single product without any other penalty.
Now in this policy,
you get many options for the payout of death benefit, one
is Looms. Suppose a person had taken an insurance of Rs 1 crore and
died, his nominee
can take Rs 1 crore at one go. The
second option is that he can take
83% of the insurance i.e. 83000
for the next 10 years. The third
option is that he can take it every month. That
too, his income will increase by 10% every year. He
can also take that option and the
last option is that he can decide himself that
give me this much percentage at once. Rest,
you give income every month after having children. So,
in the date manifest also, you
get many options for taking income,
whose name is Life Stage Benefit. Here,
whatever changes come in life,
you get marriage, birth of children, so as
your responsibilities increase
You should also increase your insurance tax. Now
what will you do for this? You will be
better off taking a separate term plan. You
can create your insurance tax in this plan itself. For
example, if you have an insurance tax of ₹1 crore,
when you get married,
you can add an insurance tax of ₹50 lakhs. You
can take 50% of this insurance tax, even a maximum of 50%. So, 50 lakhs, you will have
insurance of ₹10,000 crores. When
your first child is born, or legally, even if
you adopt, you can add
25% of your insurance or a maximum of ₹25 lakhs
there. So, at the
time of the child's birth, your
insurance tax becomes ₹95 crores. Now, if
your second child is born, or legally,
or you add this, at that time also, you can add
25% of your basic insurance or a maximum of
₹25 lakhs to the insurance tax
in this plan itself, which means
your total insurance tax will now become ₹2 crores. There is a
unique feature called Smart
Exit Option. This is a very good option.  But for
example, if a 35-year-old person
takes a policy term of 50 years, that is, policy coverage till the age of 85 years, he purchases insurance for ₹1 crore,
he
selects limited premium payment and
its expert premium is charged.
Now, in this option, the policy term should be at least 25 years
or the person should be 60
years old, so this is the smart person's option,
and you cannot do this in the last 5 years of the policy.
Now, suppose the customer's age is
70 and he thinks that now he should cancel the
policy, or if at the
time of 60, if he wants to cancel the policy
and
withdraw the entire money, then he can do so. So, this is an
excellent option where you can
get your entire money back. If you are 60 or
after this, or if the policy term is at least 25 years, then
you can withdraw the entire money
and cancel the policy.
When you feel that you are 68 and I am
retired, I do
not need insurance, then you can withdraw the money.  You can
close the policy.
If you feel that for some reason you have to
cancel the policy, then you can
cancel it back at the company within 15 days and
get the money. In this policy, you will get a
grace period of 30-3. Suppose you are
purchasing the policy on 17 September 2023,
your premium will be due on 17 September 2024. If
you are paying the new premium at that time, then
you will have one month's time till October 17,
so you can continue the policy by paying the premium there also. The
policy will
not lapse and your insurance tax will start.
Friends, the revival period given in the policy is
5 years. Suppose due to some reason you are
not able to pay the premium for a year or two, then
you can get your medical test done by paying the late fee and
start the policy again. You
can get married. In this policy, you will
also get tax benefit under Section 80C of Income Tax and the
maturity or death benefit will also be taxable in 10-10 days under Section 80C of Income Tax. So,
in this policy,  It is also available
for which you can choose to pay for only 10 years for free
or pay till you are 60, you
can select any of the two options
and you can insure yourself till 99 years,
now you have taken a full light policy till 99 years, that is, it is a
simple thing that
if anything happens to you before 99, whatever insurance tax is one crore, two crore,
10 crore, it is
your legacy, it is your will which you are
giving to your family, so the
insurance itself also reduces a will,
you have not earned any income yet, you are going to
earn in the feature, but
you can write this today in 2030 also, in the
undertaking guidelines for taking this term plan, it is
necessary to be a graduate, if you are a graduate then you
can take this policy, if you are salaried then the
minimum income should be Rs. 300000, if you are a
businessman or self-employed then your minimum
income should be Rs. 5 lakh, let us talk about
how much insurance tax you will get, so
if you are from 18 onwards  If you are between 35 years
then you will get 25 times your income, if you are between 36 to 40 then you will get
20 times, if you are between 48 to 45 then you will get
times, if you are between 46 to 50
then you will get 10 times your income as
insurance tax
and if you are between 56 to 65 years then
whatever is your annual income of last 2 years
or 3 years, you can get 5 times your average income as
insurance tax. Let's
talk about medical grid, then according to further, you
can see 35 to 45, 46 to 50 separately on this, you can get
insurance tax from 25 to 50
lakh, 50 lakh to 1 crore, it
comes in the screen as per the credit, you will get
medical test,
what documents do you have to give, you have to give your
Aadhar card, PAN card,
your photo, you have to give a cheque or you are making
online payment and whatever
financial you have to give  In that, if you are a sales person
then you have to provide 3 months salary slip, 6 months
bank statement, if you are a businessman then
you have to provide 3 years' ID with
computation pay, if your husband's insurance of ₹1 crore is already
running in ICC or he is making the purchase and
he wants to insure his wife as well
but the wife does
not have income, she is a housewife and is
educated, then 50% of the husband's income i.e.
50 lakhs will be available, if you take 2 crores
then the wife can also
get a term plan of 50 lakhs on top of the husband's income under joint life,
but you have searched that the husband has a
good income
or you want to buy and you can purchase this policy of white graduate
business insurance, nurse's business
insurance,
if the
NRI is in India for 15 days and has
standard income proof following the old guidelines, then you
can purchase this policy.
So you can take it. What documents will you need for this?
Company's PAN card will be required
Company's address proof will be required
Life Assure's PAN card
3 months salary slip Live episode Colors
6 months bank statement in which salary is being
credited Company's logs 3 years
audit Profit and loss account of the company's
last three sales statements with less competition
page Company's Amway
and organization's Articles of Association and Excel One
and you will be required on the company's letterhead
Beneficial Ownership Declaration required
on the company's letterhead and Life Associate
Vaccination will also be required and if there is any
already existing insurance policy then
you will have to give information about that too So these
documents will be required for the employer.
Now what will be the benefit to the
employer in this that whatever you enter here for free will become an
expense for your business, so here you can
avail tax benefit under section 37/1 of Income Tax. Let us
tell you in a better way that if
I have taken an insurance policy then  Keyman, such as a
person whose death
can impact the company's profit, who is the
director of the glide company, they are
called keyman, so if the company
purchases a policy for them, then what
documents will be required for that, company's PAN card, any
company's address proof, you can open it like this,
except money, Aadhar card, photo, last three years' income,
company's ITR questionnaire,
life associate's vaccination
details, insurance details, most of which will require the same
details
and if you want to take a partnership insurance policy,
like if two or
more people have worked together,
open a partnership form, then the partners
can also take this term plan for themselves under the partnership form, for this you will have to give the company the company's
PAN card, company's address
information, all these
documents  You
can also take partnership insurance by taking a policy.
In employer, employee and partnership firm,
you can take insurance up to 5 times the net profit or 3 times the gross profit. In case of a
normal
individual, according to his income, for example, between 18 to
35, you get 25 times. In this
way, you can purchase.
Now let us understand the illustration of this product,
how the illustration works.
He selects a policy term of 40 years,
where the premium without GST is Rs 152. The
policy will run for 10 years and
he is taking insurance of Rs 1 crore, that is, he is
taking the first option of
life insurance. Here, he is
not purchasing a critical incident rider,
so his premium with GST will be Rs
79,240. In doing so, we
talk about claim settlement
and provide you tax benefits.
Now, see here, the name of a 40-year-old
person.  His name is Anil Rajpurohit, he is
purchasing ICC Prudent Smart Plane, the
insurance tax is Rs 1 crore, he is
paying the premium for 10 years
and here he has selected a policy term of 40 years, the
truth is the
premium is Rs 152, 18% is being added in GST,
so along with GST the
customer will have to increase the premium of Rs 79000, after 10 years the
policy will last for 40 years, the benefit of Rs 1 crore is the
earlier option, now let us see if the
customer is taking a joint life policy, that is, he is
taking insurance of both husband and wife under the same policy, suppose the husband is
years old and he is 40 years old, he is selecting the policy term, the
insurance amount of the husband is Rs 1
crore, the insurance amount of the wife is
50% of that, i.e. Rs 50 lakh, even if it is less here, it will
work if the housewife,
both husband and wife can be insured,
here you will see the premium of the husband is
Rs 2586, now the insurance of the wife is Rs 12847  The
premium has to be paid for 25 years, the
premium is given for 60 only and the wife has to
pay for 27 years, that is, the
premium has to be paid only till both of them turn 60 and the
policy will run for 40 years. Now let us see that the
husband is 35 years old, he has an
insurance of Rs 1 crore on limited basis, that is, he has to
pay the premium till he reaches 60 years, that is, the
premium has to be paid for 25 years. The
policy is running for 40 years,
his premium is Rs 25000
with GST, the premium of the husband is Rs 30000, if
you look downwards, you will
get a policy for the wife as well and there is bike
insurance tax, that is, the premium has to be
paid for 27 years, the policy will run for 40 years
and here the premium of the wife's lover is
Rs 12800.47, which is Rs 15160 according to GST,
so 15160 plus
you will get insurance tax of Rs 1 crore for the husband and Rs 50 lakh for the wife.
Now let's see next  The option
where you are getting insurance tax online
means it will last for 100 years,
see here up to 99 years, in this company
you can also purchase a policy for up to 100 years, you can purchase a
whole life policy,
here the premium is 20 years, customer
care 40 years, that is,
I have taken it for 60 years, pay the premium till 60 years, the
policy will last for 10 years, here there is an insurance tax of 1 crore
and the
premium which will come with GST will be 88000 in
which you will also get a tax benefit of 86,
I have already told you in the company's big, like
here again there is 40 years, there is an
insurance tax, I have taken the option of 60 years,
59 years and the policy will run, the
premium is 75000, with GST the
premium is 889130913, so you
can also take a full life policy and now we are taking the
last option which can be of one which has
critical  There is also an insurance, there
is an accidental rider and there is also a normal tax.
You will get terminal illness in every option,
it comes in built only. If you
pick up any option and see, then I will
tell you here, in short, it will be written here,
see, this terminal is written,
waiver of premium on permanent
disabilities, waiver of premium on permanent disabilities,
what is the inbuilt in every option
and you get insurance tax on death due to terminal,
this is also inbuilt in every option,
for this you do not have to pay a separate premium,
if you take this option of
waiver of premium on disabilities in other companies, then
you have to pay a separate premium, but
here there is nothing like that, you
get it inbuilt, so now let us see, this is the last
and final option, in this you have been given in all the three options
that you have to pay a premium of Rs 30689, the
person is 35 years old, he is
paying premium for 25 years, he is
taking the policy till 75 years, that is, he is taking it for 40 years, he is taking a
normal tax of Rs 1 crore,
₹1 lakh  That is
critical, you can take
as much as you want, ₹15 lakh, ₹10 lakh, as per your requirement. You are
taking accidental benefit of ₹50 lakh,
accident benefit, as you know, in case of
death in an accident, ₹50 lakh gets
doubled to ₹1 crore, so this will become ₹1 crore
and ₹1 crore basic tax, so
you get ₹2 crore,
see here it is also written in basic
and you are getting premium permanent disability,
now you will see here that
under medical you get income tax benefit, in this
you already know about the company's big
and in this way you will see
how you have to pay insurance tax of ₹1 crore
till the end, there is premium payment for 25 years, the
policy is running for 40 years, you are
purchasing the option of these one because
you are getting all the options, here you are
getting normal tax,
accidental tax for ₹30000,
practical healthness for ₹4225, your total for ₹1243  The
premium is Rs 36,000 for the battery. In this way,
you can see all the options along with the equipment. So,
this is a good product. The company's
claim settlement ratio has been very strong for many years. The
company is very strong. The
company has been operating in the market for 23 years. The
riders behind the product are very good. The critical
insurance policy is running.
Your premium payment is waived for disabilities. You are getting
double insurance policy in case of an accident. You are getting Rs
34,000 critical insurance
benefit. If
you see this premium comparatively with other companies, it is
lower than most of the companies.
This product can be very good for you in terms of smoke rate. So, in
this way, if you
want to take a policy in your company or an employer, then
you
can also purchase different business insurance policies. There are many
multiple options available. So,
if you want to purchase this policy, you
can WhatsApp me on my mobile number 9909403412. As
you know, I have done a lot of comparisons.  I will
tell you which
company is giving which star on higher insurance,
which organization is giving which star on lower insurance,
which star is giving on smoke rate, its
features are good, so if you are buying from someone, then if you
buy after comparing,
you can get more benefit,
so if you liked my video, then before
leaving,
definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel,
like the video, if possible, share it,
Jai Hind